Gabriel Sackitey

+233559016835 | mrgabby0@gmail.com | Linkedln: https://bit.ly/3a0f66u | Github: https://github.com/Mr-Gabby

SUMMARY

Data Analyst with 1+ year of experience interpreting and analyzing data in order to drive successful business solutions. Proficient knowledge in statistics, mathematics and analytics. Excellent understanding of business operations and analytics tools for effective analyses of data.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Data Analysis
- SQL
- Python (Basic)
- Tableau
- Google Analytics
- Excel
- R
- Power BI

WORK EXPERIENCE

DATA ANALYST

Ghana Armed Forces (Army Secretary Department) (July 2021 – Present)

- Researched and resolved issues regarding integrity of data flow into databases.
- Collaborated with unit leaders to identify and prioritize problems related to deployment of military personnels.
- Utilized data visualization tools to effectively communicate military insights using Tableau dashboards.
- Extracted and interpreted data patterns to translate findings into actionable outcomes.
- Developed tables, views and materialized views using SQL.
- Used statistical methods to analyze data and generate useful reports
- Presenting information generated from data to the Army Secretary.

IT SUPPORT OFFICER (National Service)

Ghana Armed Forces (August 2019 – August 2020)

- installing and configuring software, hardware, and networks.
- Monitoring system performance and troubleshooting issues.
- Ensuring security and efficiency of IT infrastructure.
- Developing expertise to train staff on new technologies.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Science

Computer Science, Coventry University United Kingdom, November 2019

Diploma

Information Technology, Ghana Technology University College,

Ghana, July 2017

Business Analytics Certificate

Azubi Africa, March 2022 - May 2022

(Excel, Knime, SQL, Python)

Google Data Analyst Certification

Coursera, April 2022 - Present (Yet to be completed)

PERSONAL SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

- Ability to manage multiple projects in parallel
- Ability to use appropriate language in all situations.
- Creative and able to think outside the box
- Ability to adapt to new changes and learning quickly